AMIT KUMAR

Phone: +91-7493820347 Email: amitkumar225176@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/amitkumar-dev/

Address: Ranchi, Jharkhand, India, 835222

SUMMARY

Software Quality Assurance Engineer with 1 yr 10 mos of experience in Software Testing and 1 year of experience in Web Development. Experienced in Automation Testing (Katalon Studio) and Manual testing. As a Quality Assurance Engineer, I am skilled in functional testing, Downstream testing, Regression testing, and Automation testing. Extensive experience in SDLC and Agile Methodology. Seeking a technically challenging position in Software Testing.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cognizant Technology and Solutions, India October 2021 – July 2023 | Kolkata, India

- As a Quality Assurance Engineer, I worked for Great American Insurance Group (GAIG) where I was responsible for
 ensuring quality and ensuring there should be zero Defect Leakage.
- · Creating and documenting test plans, test scenarios, test cases, and test scripts.
- · Developing and running test automation scripts in a web services development environment.
- Experienced in Test automation, execution, Defect reporting, and resolution.
- · Integration with Jenkins.
- Experienced in SDLC, STLC, and Insurance domains.
- Involved in Downstream Testing using SQL developer to ensure the data was being flown downstream..
- In-sprint Testing: Demonstrated experience in analyzing requirements from user stories and conducting effective insprint testing to ensure software aligns with user needs and is defect-free.
- Collaboration with Development Teams: Collaborated with the development team and product owner throughout all
 phases of development, including performing in-sprint testing and providing valuable feedback for improvements.
- Proficiently managed the defect lifecycle via Rally, skillful capturing, tracking, and prioritizing bugs to ensure timely resolution; additionally, identified and addressed over 60 defects spanning multiple Business units.
- Test Data Preparation and Execution: Proven experience in preparing test data for test cases and executing them.
- Utilized Agile methodologies, collaborated with teams, and Attended Scrum, Sprint planning, and Daily Stand-ups.

Brahm Technology Pvt. Ltd, India

December 2020 - October 2021 | Jharkhand, India

- As a Web Developer, I worked for Brahm Technology Pvt. Ltd. where I was responsible for Web Development, and Web hosting. Worked with senior developers on critical projects and delivered the given task under ECD.
- Experienced in web development using HTML, CSS, JS, Bootstrap, and in backend PHP and MySQL.

PROJECT DETAILS

Great American Insurance Group (GAIG) December 2021 – July 2023 Great American Insurance Group is engaged primarily in property and casualty insurance ("P&C"), focusing on specialized commercial products for businesses. The Test team is responsible for end-to-end execution. Spearheaded diverse testing methodologies, including automation, system integration, Automation Testing, Manual Testing, Downstream testing, and regression testing, resulting in consistently high-quality deliverables

SKILLS

- Katalon Studio, Groovy, Core JAVA, HTML, CSS, PHP, and MySQL
- BDD Cucumber, Jenkins, Rally, Jira
- Git and GitHub
- · Agile-Methodology
- Test Planning, Test Scripting, Test Execution.
- Web Development and Web Hosting

CERTIFICATIONS

 Selenium WebDriver with Java - Basics to Advance + Frameworks from Udemy

EDUCATION

Marwari College Ranchi (Bachelors of Computer Application 2017 - 2020)

• 70.43%

OP Jindal School Patratu (Intermediate 2015 - 2017)

• 67.5%

OP Jindal School Patratu (Matriculation 2005 - 2015)

• 9.4 CGPA

LANGUAGE

- English
- Hindi

DECLARATION